<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>K.M.F. Trading Journal Blog</title>
    <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog</link>
    <description>Trading insights, app guides, and tips for serious traders. The K.M.F. Trading Journal blog.</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://kmfjournal.com/blog/rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <image>
      <url>https://kmfjournal.com/logo.png</url>
      <title>K.M.F. Trading Journal Blog</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog</link>
    </image>

    <item>
      <title>Profit Factor vs Win Rate: Which Metric Actually Predicts Trading Success?</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/profit-factor-vs-win-rate</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/profit-factor-vs-win-rate</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Statistics</category>
      <description>Most traders obsess over win rate, but profit factor is a far better predictor of long-term success. See the math that reveals why a 70% win rate trader can be losing money while a 40% win rate trader thrives.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The 1% Risk Rule: The Trading Rule That Keeps Professional Traders Alive</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/1-percent-risk-rule</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/1-percent-risk-rule</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Risk Management</category>
      <description>Learn why professional traders never risk more than 1% per trade, how to calculate exact position sizes using the rule, and how it protects your account during the losing streaks that are mathematically inevitable.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Revenge Trading: What It Is, Why It Happens, and How to Break the Cycle</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/revenge-trading</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/revenge-trading</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Psychology</category>
      <description>Revenge trading is one of the fastest ways to blow a trading account. Understand the psychology of loss aversion and ego that drives it, and learn five practical techniques to stop the cycle before it starts.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Do a Weekly Trading Review (With a Complete Template)</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/weekly-trading-review-template</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/weekly-trading-review-template</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Improvement</category>
      <description>The difference between traders who improve and those who repeat the same mistakes is a systematic weekly review. A step-by-step guide across five areas, with a complete 15-question template you can use immediately.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>R-Multiple Explained: How to Measure Trade Quality (Not Just Profit)</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/r-multiple-explained</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/r-multiple-explained</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Statistics</category>
      <description>Dollar P/L is one of the least informative metrics in trading. R-multiple — actual P/L divided by your initial risk — is the honest way to evaluate every trade. Learn how to calculate it and use it to find your real edge.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Why You Break Your Own Trading Rules — And How to Stop</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/why-traders-break-their-rules</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/why-traders-break-their-rules</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Psychology</category>
      <description>You wrote the rules yourself. You know they work. So why do you keep breaking them? The science of System 1 vs System 2 thinking explains almost every instance of rule-breaking — and the solutions are practical, not motivational.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Recover from a Losing Streak Without Blowing Your Account</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/how-to-recover-from-losing-streak</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/how-to-recover-from-losing-streak</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Psychology</category>
      <description>Losing streaks are mathematically inevitable even in profitable strategies. A step-by-step recovery framework: how to assess whether it is variance or a broken edge, reduce size correctly, and return to full trading gradually.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>10 Questions Every Trader Should Ask After Every Trade</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/10-questions-after-every-trade</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/10-questions-after-every-trade</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Improvement</category>
      <description>Most traders check their P/L and move on. The traders who accelerate their development ask deeper questions after every trade. These 10 post-trade review questions separate process quality from random outcomes.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Trading Expectancy Explained: The Formula That Tells If Your Strategy Works</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/trading-expectancy-explained</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/trading-expectancy-explained</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Statistics</category>
      <description>Expectancy is the one number that reveals whether your strategy is profitable long-term. Learn the formula, see it applied to different win rate and R:R combinations, and calculate your own expectancy from trade history.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>How to Set a Stop Loss Properly (Not Just Randomly)</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/how-to-set-stop-loss</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/how-to-set-stop-loss</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Risk Management</category>
      <description>Most traders place stop losses based on arbitrary pip counts or dollar amounts. Learn the three professional methods — structure-based, ATR-based, and candle-based — that place stops where the market actually invalidates your trade.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Position Sizing Guide: How Much Should You Trade?</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/position-sizing-guide</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/position-sizing-guide</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Risk Management</category>
      <description>Two traders, identical strategies, one blows up and one grows consistently. The difference is almost always position sizing. The exact formula for forex, stocks, and crypto — with worked examples for each market.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>The Pre-Trade Checklist: 10 Things to Verify Before Every Trade Entry</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/pre-trade-checklist</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/pre-trade-checklist</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>Discipline</category>
      <description>Pilots and surgeons use checklists before every consequential action. Traders should too. A 10-point pre-trade checklist covering technical, risk, and psychological criteria — and why the discipline of skipping trades matters as much as taking them.</description>
    </item>

    <item>
      <title>Best Free Trading Journal App for Android in 2026</title>
      <link>https://kmfjournal.com/blog/best-free-trading-journal-app-android-2026</link>
      <guid isPermaLink="true">https://kmfjournal.com/blog/best-free-trading-journal-app-android-2026</guid>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Feb 2026 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <category>App Reviews</category>
      <description>An honest comparison of K.M.F., TraderSync, Tradervue and Edgewonk — features, pricing, and which is actually best for forex, stock and crypto traders on mobile.</description>
    </item>

  </channel>
</rss>
